所以，这不是很好。
So, this isn't great.
所以让我们继续制作一个类型，它可以做我们想要它做的事情。
So let's go ahead and make a type that does what we want it to do.
所以取得成功，那将需要一些x。
So make a Success, and that'll be take some x.
所以把这个 x 带入 concat，另一个，other.x。
And so take this x into concat, another one, other.x.
我们必须保持在类型内，对吗？
We gotta stay within the type, right?
所以我们要做成功和失败。
So we're gonna make Success and a failure.
他们都是，我们要定义这个
And they're both, we're gonna kinda define this
作为验证结果超类的子类或其他东西。
as subclasses of the superclass of validation result or something.
所以它是封闭的，因为它会
So it's closed in that it will
无论成功还是失败，始终向您返回验证结果。
always return you a validation result whether that's a success or a failure.
与Either一样，
Same thing with Either,
当您连接到Either 时，您并不总是能立即恢复原状。
you don't always get it right back when you concat to Either.
就像你可以向右或向左一样。
Like you can get it right or left.
它在任何类型的保护伞下关闭。
It's closed under the Either type umbrella.
但我们将在这里做同样的事情。
But so we'll do the same thing here.
所以我们会说让我们做一个失败。
So we'll say let's make a Fail.
我们会在这里说 isFail 这样我们就知道它是什么了。
We'll say like isFail here so we know what it is.
[笑] 而且 isFail：这里是假的，所以。
[LAUGH] And isFail: false up here, so that.
如果另一个我会说好的
I will say okay if the other one
isFail，那么我们要做的就是保留另一个，对吧？
isFail, then what we want to do is keep the other one, right?
因为那就像我不想那样，我总是想保留失败。
Because that's just like I don't want to, I always want to keep the failures.
但如果没有，我们会保持自己，并且
But if not, we'll keep ourselves, and
我们将用 x 重建一个 Success ，很酷。
we'll just reconstruct a Success with x, cool.
你知道，如果我们在一个班级，我们可以这样做，但我只是在重新制作它。
You know, if we were in a class, we could just do this, but I'm just remaking it.
关于它是如何工作的或为什么有效的任何问题？
Any questions on how that works or why that works?
如果我试图将成功与失败联系起来，
if I'm trying to concat a success with a failure,
我要保留失败，因为我希望失败继续
I'm gonna keep the failure because I want the failure to continue
就成为结果，因为我不想不小心通过。
on to be the result, because I don't want to accidentally pass.
有了失败，我们会说得很好，所以我知道我是个失败者。
And with Fail, we'll say well, so I know I'm a failure.
[笑]我知道我很失败。
[LAUGH] I do know I'm a failure.
但是如果另一个失败，那么我们实际上想要连接，对吗？
But if the other one is a failure, then we actually want to concat, right?
所以我们会说 other.x.concat，将我们的 x 与另一个 x 连接起来。
So we'll say other.x.concat, concat our x with the other x.
这有点像相反
This is kind of like the opposite
要么在那里，对吧？
of Either there, right?
失败现在正在连接它们，这将收集所有错误和
The failures are now concating their which would be collecting all the errors and
成功。
the success.
因此，如果另一个失败，我们实际上会将它们连接起来，
So if the other one's a failure, we'll actually concat them both,
离开把它放回失败这里。
left to put it back in the Fail here.
否则，我们只会保持自己，甜蜜。
And otherwise, we'll just keep ourselves, sweet.
好吧，看起来它可能有用，让我们试一试。
All right, that looks like it might work, let's give it a shot.
我们会说，好吧，我们会做一个成功，而不是一个权利。
And we'll say, all right, instead of a Right, we'll do a Success.
而不是左派，我们会失败。
Instead of a Left, we'll do a fail.
让我们看看这里发生了什么。
And let's see what's happening here.
运行它，另一个爆炸。
Run it, another blow up.
这是一个，我无法在第一次尝试时就得到它，我不知道你们都是如何编程的，但是
It's a, I can't ever get it on the first try, I don't know how you all program but
我很烂。
I suck.
[笑] 所以 type 是 81，它说 other.fold 不是一个函数，好吧。
[LAUGH] So type is 81, it says other.fold is not a function, all right.
让我们看看这里发生了什么，可能看起来像。
Let's see what's happening here, looks like perhaps.
我有一个 concat，我有一个 concat，返回成功和失败。
I have a concat, I have a concat, returning Success and a failure.
我们从“要么”开始，就这样。
We're starting with an Either, there we go.
所以让我们从 Success 开始，
So let's start with a Success with that in there,
因为我试图比较两种不同的东西。
because I'm trying to compare two different things.
仍然爆炸，相同的功能。
And still blew up, same function.
它实际上在这里。
It's actually here.
德普，在我回来之前要么折叠起来。
Derp, before I was returning Either in folding it out.
实际上，让我们在这里做一个漂亮的小折叠，这样我们就可以摆脱这里的类型。
Actually, let's make a nice little fold here so we can get out of our type here.
所以我们得到 af 和 ag，就像两者一样。
So we get a f and a g, just like Either.
在 Success 案例中，我们将使用 x 运行右侧。
And on the Success case, we'll run the right side with x.
在他失败的情况下，我们将运行左边的 f。
And on he Fail case, we will run the f, the left one.
好吧，就像Either一样，这将命中console.error或console.log。
All right, so just like Either, this will hit the console.error or the console.log.
我们走了。
And there we go.
我们得到什么？
What do we get?
我们明白了，这是行不通的。
We get, well this isn't working.
[笑] 所以看起来我们没有通过它就通过了。
[LAUGH] So looks like we passed it without it getting through.
这是怎么运作的？
How's that working?
我们有一个对象键的规范，我们正在运行这个函数。
We have a spec of an object key, and we're running this function.
如果返回true，则为Success，如果返回false，则为Fail。
If it returns true, it will be a Success, if returns false, it is a Fail.
所以我们仍然收到电子邮件为空，这很高兴。
So we're still getting the email as empty and it's happy.
如果我们抬头看这里，我们可以看到我实际上是
And if we look up here, we can see that I'm actually
在 x 上调用 IsFail，我不想这样做，我想在类型本身上调用它。
calling IsFail on the x, I don't wanna do that, I wanna call it on the type itself.
所以在那里，在那里，那里有一个小错误。
So there, and up here, a little typo over there.
这应该可以解决问题，让我们看看会发生什么。
And that should do the trick, let's see what happens.
我们走了，电子邮件不好。
There we go, email bad.
如果我两者都做，我们会得到两者吗？
If I do both, do we get both?
我们做到了，我们都得到了，太棒了。
We do, we get both, awesome.
如果我输入姓名、brian 和电子邮件，我们会收到吗？
If I put in a name, brian, and an email do we get?
@hello.com，这里发生了什么？
@hello.com, what happens here?
太好了，我们得到了一个只有对象的数组，太棒了。
Great, we get an array of just the object, terrific.